zeldawiki.org 2019-12-21

# Privacy Policy | Fandom

Date of last revision: November 18, 2019

This Privacy Policy applies to your use of the services and sites listed in Annex A hereto (collectively, the “Services”) provided, owned, or operated by Fandom, Inc. (with its affiliates, “Fandom”). For clarity, this privacy policy does not apply to fandom.com, wikia.com and wikia.org (including all subdomains) and our mobile apps under the Fandom brand, all of which are governed by the privacy policy located at https://www.fandom.com/privacy-policy.

Fandom values the privacy of users, subscribers, publishers, members, and others who visit and use the Services (collectively or individually, “you” or “users”) and wants you to be familiar with how we collect, use, and disclose personal information from and about you.

This privacy policy implements the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), a data protection law that applies where we process personal information of anyone located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”). We have added sections at the end of this privacy policy which apply solely to EEA residents.

For purposes of data protection laws, Fandom, Inc., located at 130 Sutter Street, 4th Floor, San Francisco, CA 94104, is the “data controller” of your information with respect to data collected pursuant to the Services.

You may share personal information when using the Services. One example is when you provide information about yourself as part of the account creation process. Another is when you take certain actions on the Services that are public or intended to be public in nature, such as when you participate in a chat room, post profile information, or follow a channel. Given the social nature of some of the Services, that information may be collected, used, or disclosed by others who are part of that social interaction. In addition, some features of the Services are designed to provide others with information about user activity. We encourage you to be mindful of this when considering your activity on the Services.

By agreeing to this Privacy Policy in your account setup, or by using the Services, you consent to the extent permitted by law to the information handling practices described in this Policy. 

## Personal Information We Collect About You

We obtain information about you through the means discussed below when we provide the Services. Please note that we need certain types of information so that we can provide the Services to you. If you do not provide us with such information, or ask us to delete it, you may no longer be able to access or use the Services.

  * **User-provided Information:** You may provide a variety of information about yourself to us, such as your name, email address, postal mailing address, telephone number, credit card number, and billing information when you register for Services; upload, purchase, view, or download certain content or products from the Services; enter contests or sweepstakes; or otherwise use the features and functionality of the Services.
  * **Automatically Collected Information:** When you access the Services or open one of our emails, we automatically record and store certain information about your system by using cookies and other types of technologies. Cookies are small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters that are sent to your browser. For information about what cookies are, how they work, how we use them, and how to remove them, please see the Cookie Policy section below. Examples of such information we automatically collect include Internet Protocol address (“IP Address”), a unique user ID, device and browser types and identifiers, referring and exit page addresses, software and system type, and information about your usage of Services. Examples of how we use automatically collected information include to: (a) automatically update our application on your system; (b) remember your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you access the Services; (c) provide customized advertisements, content, and information; (d) monitor the effectiveness of marketing campaigns; (e) monitor and store aggregate site usage metrics such as total number of visitors and pages accessed; and (f) track your entries, submissions, and status in any promotions or other activities.
  * **Information from Other Sources:** We may obtain additional information such as demographic and statistical information from third parties and sources other than the Services, such as advertisers or social media networks (such as Facebook) for which you have approved our access. When you access the Services through social media networks or when you connect the Services to social media networks, you are authorizing us to collect, store, and use such additional information and content in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We may also obtain information from third-party services regarding your use of such services, including about your use of the content you choose to broadcast through the Services. We use this information to supplement the information we collect about you in order to provide more relevant, safer experiences for you with the Services and improve the Services, analytics, and advertising. If we combine or associate information from other sources with information that we collect through the Services, we will treat the combined information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## How We Use Personal Information

  * We use such information to operate, maintain, enhance, provide, create, and develop all of the features, functionality, and services (new or existing) found on the Services; provide security for our websites, products, software, or applications; manage relationships with account holders, including making or receiving payment; improve your experience with the Services by providing content recommendations and by delivering content that we hope you will find relevant and interesting, including advertising and marketing messages; allow you to comment on content, and participate in online games, contests, or rewards programs; prevent fraud and abuse; and understand the usage trends of our users.
  * We use your email address to communicate with you, including to notify you of major Services updates, for customer service purposes, or to contact you regarding any content that you have posted to or downloaded from the Services.
  * We may periodically send promotional materials or notifications to you related to the Services. If you want to stop receiving promotional materials, you can go to your account settings once you have logged in to the Services or follow the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of any email from us. If you have installed a mobile app and you wish to stop receiving push notifications, you can change the settings either on your mobile device or through the app.
  * In certain cases, we have a legal obligation to collect and process your personal information (such as our obligation to share data with tax authorities).
  * We may also ask for your consent to process your personal information for a specific purpose that we communicate to you. When you consent to our processing your personal information for a specified purpose, you may withdraw your consent at any time and we will stop processing of your data for that purpose.
  * We will rely on legal grounds to process your personal information to the extent permitted by applicable law, which may include, without limitation: to honor contractual commitments, to take steps in anticipation of entering into contract, to fulfill legal obligations, your consent, and our legitimate interests.

## When We Disclose Personal Information

We share such information as described below:

  * We disclose such information to service providers working on our behalf, such as, to: provide website hosting, maintenance, and security services; fulfill orders; conduct data analysis and create reports; offer certain functionality; or assist us in improving the Services and creating new services and features. We require that these parties process such information in compliance with this Privacy Policy, we authorize them to use the information only for the purposes for which it is provided to them, and we require them to use reasonable confidentiality measures.
  * We may make information available to our affiliates (meaning entities controlled by, controlling, or under common control with us).
  * We may disclose user information if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to comply with U.S. state and federal laws or other applicable laws around the world (for example, in the country of your residence), or respond to a court order, judicial or other government request, subpoena, or warrant in the manner legally required.
  * We also reserve the right to disclose information that we believe, in good faith, is appropriate or necessary to protect us from potential liability or from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses; investigate and defend ourselves against third-party claims, or allegations; protect the security or integrity of the Services; or protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our users, or others.

Other than as set out above, you will receive notice when personal information about you might be shared with third parties and you will have an opportunity to choose not to share the information.

## Cookie Policy

Fandom uses certain technologies in connection with the Services to collect information that helps us improve your online experience. In this Cookie Policy, we refer to these technologies, which include cookies, pixels, web beacons, and gifs, collectively as “cookies.” This policy explains the different types of cookies used on the Services and how you can control them. 

## What Is A Cookie?

Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer or mobile device. They are widely used in order to make websites and software applications work, or work in a better, more efficient way. They can do this because websites and software applications can read and write these files, enabling them to recognize you and remember important information that will make your use of a website or software application more convenient (e.g., by remembering your user preferences).

## What Cookies Do We Use?

Below we list the different types of cookies we may use on the Services.

## “Non-Marketing Cookies”

“Non-Marketing Cookies” consist of the below-described essential, performance and functionality cookies. 

**Essential Cookies** : These cookies are essential to the operation of the Services in order to enable you to move around it and to use its features. Without these cookies, services you have asked for, such as accessing secure areas of the website or paid for content, cannot be provided. These cookies are essential for using the website and therefore cannot be turned off without severely affecting your use of the website.

**Performance Cookie** s: Performance cookies, which often include analytics cookies, collect information about your use of this Services and enable us to improve the way it works. For example, performance cookies show us which are the most frequently visited pages on the website, allow us to see the overall patterns of usage on the Services, help us record any difficulties you have with the Services and show us whether our advertising is effective or not.

**Functionality Cookies** : In some circumstances, we may use functionality cookies. Functionality cookies allow us to remember the choices you make on the Services and to provide enhanced and more personalized features, such as customising a certain webpage, remembering if we have asked you to participate in a promotion and for other services you request, like watching a video or commenting on a blog. All of these features help us to improve your visit to the Service.

## “Marketing Cookies”

We and our service providers may use targeting or advertising cookies (referred to herein as “Marketing Cookies”) to deliver ads that we believe are more relevant to you and your interests. For example, we may use targeting or advertising cookies to limit the number of times you see the same ad on our Services and to help measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns. These cookies remember what you have looked at on the Services and we may share this information with other organizations, such as advertisers.

For more information about Marketing Cookies and how you can opt out, you can visit youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices or allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html

Flash Cookies: We may, in certain situations, use Adobe Flash Player to deliver special content, such as video clips or animation. To improve your user experience, Local Shared Objects (commonly known as “Flash cookies”) are employed to provide functions such as remembering your settings and preferences. Flash cookies are stored on your device, but they are managed through an interface different from the one provided by your web browser. This means it is not possible to manage Flash cookies at the browser level, in the same way you would manage cookies. Instead, you can access your Flash management tools from Adobe’s website directly. The Adobe website provides comprehensive information on how to delete or disable Flash cookies see adobe.com/security/flashplayer for further information. Please be aware that if you disable or reject Flash cookies for the Service, you may not be able to access certain features, such as video content or services that require you to sign in.

## How Do Third Parties Use Cookies On The Site?

In some circumstances, we may work with third parties to provide services on the Service.  
In addition, third-party advertisers and other organizations may use their own cookies to collect information about your activities on the Services websites and/or the advertisements you have clicked on. This information may be used by them to serve advertisements that they believe are most likely to be of interest to you based on content you have viewed. Third-party advertisers may also use this information to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements.

We do not control these cookies. To disable or reject third-party cookies, please refer to the relevant third party’s website. You can also learn more about controlling cookies in the “How do I control Cookies” section below.

## How Do I Control Cookies?

You may refuse to accept cookies from the Services at any time by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse cookies. You can refuse to accept Flash cookies from the Services using Adobe’s Flash management tools at http://www.adobe.com/security/flashplayer. Further information about the procedure to follow in order to disable cookies can be found on your Internet browser provider’s website via your help screen. You may wish to refer to allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html for information on commonly used browsers. Please be aware that if cookies are disabled, not all features of the Services may operate as intended.

## Data Subject Rights and Your Choices

You may decline to share certain information with us, in which case we may not be able to provide to you some of the features and functionality found on the Services. If you have created an account, depending on the service, you may be able to update your profile information and preferences or disable your account by logging in and going to the settings page. For requests to review, update, delete, or otherwise limit our use of information that you have provided directly to us, you may contact support@fandom.com. In your request, please include your email address, name, address, and telephone number and specify all relevant background. To protect your privacy and security, we may take steps to verify your identity before granting you access or making corrections to your information. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information at all times.

## Account Closure & Deletion

If you would like to close your account and delete your profile information, you may update or delete information tied to your account, or close an account, by submitting a help ticket to that service. If you close your account, we may retain certain information about you for the activities described in this Privacy Policy, or as permitted or required by applicable law.

## Third-Party Services and Websites

The Services may link to third-party websites or services. The privacy practices of those third parties are not governed by this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of these third-party websites and services to understand their practices.

If you connect to a third-party service (such as Facebook, Twitter, or another third-party application) through the Services or otherwise link your account with a third-party service, you are requesting and authorizing us to share or grant access to information on your behalf (such as your username, the fact that your connection originated from the Services, and other relevant usage and diagnostic information) with such third party. We may also send information about your activities on the Services to such third parties. For example, we may make information available to app developers, game developers, and game publishers to facilitate purchases and awards of digital goods, such as games and in-game items.

## Advertisers and Analytics Providers

We may use third-party Web analytics services in connection with the Services, such as those of Google Analytics, and its advertising features. These service providers use a variety of tracking technologies such as cookies to analyze how users use the Services. The information collected (described above in “Automatically Collected Information”) will be collected directly by these service providers to evaluate your use of the Services. For more information on how Google Analytics uses data from our websites and how you can control the information sent to Google, see https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites. To learn about opting out of Google Analytics, see https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

Because these opt outs are cookie-based, please note that if you get a new computer or device, install or start using a new browser, or erase or alter your browser’s cookie file, you may need to opt out again.

We may allow advertisers, third-party advertising networks and third-party advertising serving companies to serve advertisements directly to you within the Services and other sites, services and software. By serving these advertisements directly to you, these companies can set their own cookies on your computer and trigger their own Web beacons and other tracking technologies to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements, and to collect and track information such as demographic information, inferred interests, aggregated information, and activity to assist them in personalizing the advertising content delivered to you. We do not provide information that is intended to identify you personally to these third-party ad servers or ad networks without your consent. However, if you respond to an advertisement that targets a certain audience (for example, males age 20 to 25 who have participated in certain promotions), the advertiser or ad-server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience that they were trying to reach.

We cannot control the tracking technologies and activities of, other advertisers, third-party advertising networks, or third-party advertising servers. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these advertisers, third-party advertising networks, or third-party advertising servers. For more information about third-party advertising networks and similar entities that use these technologies, see http://www.aboutads.info/consumers, and to opt-out of such ad networks’ and services’ advertising practices, for example, Google Analytics advertising features and Google’s use of cookies, go to the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page, the Digital Advertising Alliance opt-out page, or the Your Online Choices page.

## Do Not Track

Do Not Track (“DNT”) is a privacy preference that users can set in certain web browsers. DNT is a way for users to inform websites and services that they do not want certain information about their webpage visits collected over time and across websites or online services. We are committed to providing you with meaningful choices about the information collected on our website for third-party purposes, and that is why we provide the Network Advertising Initiative, Your Online Choices and the Digital Advertising Alliance opt-out links above. However, we do not recognize or respond to browser-initiated DNT signals.

## Data Security

We use a variety of managerial, technical, and physical measures to protect the integrity and security of your information. These measures may vary based on the sensitivity of your information. However, no security precautions or systems can be completely secure. We cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. We cannot guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.

## Retention of Your Information

We keep your personal information to enable your continued use of Services, for as long as it is required in order to fulfill the relevant purposes described in this Privacy Policy, as may be required (or permitted) by law such as for tax and accounting purposes, or as otherwise communicated to you.

## Children’s Privacy

IF YOU ARE UNDER 13 YEARS OF AGE, THEN PLEASE DO NOT USE OR ACCESS THE SERVICES AT ANY TIME OR IN ANY MANNER.

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, we do not knowingly collect or maintain personal information (as defined by the United States Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act) from persons under 13 years-of-age. If we learn that personal information of persons under 13 has been collected on or through the Services, we will take appropriate steps to delete this information.

If you are the parent or legal guardian of a child under 13 who has become a Services member, then please contact us at support@fandom.com to have that child’s account terminated and personal information deleted.

For residents of the EEA, where processing of personal information is based on consent, we will not knowingly engage in that processing for users under the age of consent established by applicable data protection law. If we learn that we are engaged in that processing with such users, we will halt such processing and will take reasonable measures to promptly remove applicable information from our records.

## Merger or Sale

In the event that we, or some or all assets related to the Services are acquired by or merged with a third-party entity or in connection with a contemplated change of ownership transaction, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information that we have collected from users as part of that merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control event, including in the course of diligence.

## International Data Transfers

Information collected by us may be stored and processed in your region, in the United States (for instance in our major data centers), or in any other country where we or our affiliates, subsidiaries, partners, or service providers are located or maintain facilities. If we provide any information about you to any such entities, we will take appropriate measures to ensure such companies protect your information adequately in accordance with this Privacy Policy and applicable law.

## Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this Privacy Policy at any time (for example to reflect updates to the Services or to reflect changes in the law). Please check this Privacy Policy periodically for those changes. Your continued use of the Services after the posting of changes constitutes your binding acceptance of such changes.

We will not materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of personal information collected in the past under a prior version of the Privacy Policy without the consent of affected individuals.

## Contact Information

We have a Data Protection Officer to assist with all queries regarding our processing of personal information; Wade Warren who can be contacted at c/o Fandom, Inc., 130 Sutter Street, 4th Floor, San Francisco, CA 94104; Email: DPO@fandom.com; Phone: (415) 980-5647. If you have any complaints about the Services, please contact us at: Address: 130 Sutter Street, 4th Floor, San Francisco, CA 94104 Email: support@fandom.com Telephone: (415) 762-0780

We will respond to your inquiry within 30 days of its receipt. If you are a California resident, you may have this same information emailed to you by sending a letter to the foregoing address with your email address and a request for this information.

## California Privacy Rights

California law permits users who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, a list of the third parties to whom we have disclosed their personal information (as defined by applicable California law) for their direct marketing purposes in the prior calendar year, as well as the type of personal information disclosed to those parties. We do not currently disclose personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.

## Additional Provisions Of This Privacy Policy That Are Applicable To EEA Residents

**What is our justification for handling your personal data?**

Under European data protection laws, we have to ensure that we process your personal information fairly and lawfully. This means that we must have a “legal basis” for each of our processing activities where they relate to the personal data of an individual within the EEA. These bases include:

  1. **Consent**  – we may decide to obtain your specific, freely given consent to one or more processing activities;
  2. **Legal obligation**  – we may need to process your data where it is necessary to comply with applicable laws that we are subject to;
  3. **Performance of a contract**  – we may process your data if we are entering into a contract with you, or taking preparatory steps to do so;
  4. **Legitimate interests**  – we may process your personal data where we believe that we have a legitimate interest in doing so, and we have analyzed this and determined that our interests are not overridden by the impact on your rights and freedoms under data protection law.

We rely on these legal bases in different ways, and in relation to different types of processing of your personal data.

_Consent_

We process your personal information collected through the use of Marketing Cookies (as described in the Cookie Policy section above) on the basis of your consent, which we ask for when you first visit our Services. You are entitled to withdraw your consent to our use of these Cookies. The list of partners for which we request consent is located at our [Vendor List](https://www.fandom.com/partner-list). In order to withdraw your consent, please visit the “Reset Your Tracking Preferences” button at the bottom of this Privacy Policy.

_Legitimate Interests_

We believe that our use of your other personal information described herein is necessary for our legitimate interests, which are as follows:

1\. To run, grow and develop our business;  
2\. To operate the Services;  
3\. For marketing, market research and business development; and  
4\. For internal administrative purposes.

If we rely on our, or another person’s, legitimate interests for using your personal information, we will undertake a balancing test to ensure that our (or the other person’s) legitimate interests are not outweighed by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms which require protection. You can ask us for information on this balancing test by using the contact details in the “Complaints, Questions and Comments” section below.

We process your personal information collected through the use of Non-Marketing Cookies (as described in the Cookie Policy section above) on the basis of our legitimate interests. We also rely on legitimate interests to use your personal information in order to provide you with access to our Services, and to make sure that they work properly, and to keep a record of who is accessing and making changes to the different parts of our Services.

## Rights Of EEA Residents

Residents in the EEA have the following rights:

1\. The right to ask us to provide you with copies of personal information that we hold about you at any time free of charge, although we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive, or repetitive. Please utilize the form found here when making this request: [Download Your Data](https://fandom.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360021403033-I-want-to-download-a-copy-of-my-data).

2\. The right to ask us to update or correct any out-of-date or incorrect personal information that we hold about you (in accordance with applicable data protection laws).

3\. The rights to request that we stop using or delete your personal information (in certain circumstances we may not be able to stop using your personal information but if that is the case, we will let you know why). Please utilize the form found here when making this request: [Right to Be Forgotten](https://fandom.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360021402973-Please-forget-my-Fandom-account).

4\. The right to opt out of any marketing communications that we (or any third party to whom we have disclosed your personal information with your consent) may send you.

If you wish to exercise any of the above rights, please use the forms indicated where applicable and email us at support@fandom.com.

We will consider all such requests and provide our response within a reasonable period (and in any event within any time period required by law). Please note, however, that certain personal information may be exempt from such requests in certain circumstances.

If an exception applies, we will tell you this when responding to your request. We may request you provide us with information necessary to confirm your identity before responding to any request you make.

Please also note for security and fraud investigation and prevention purposes, we will retain the full IP address for users located in the EEA for up to 12 months.

In addition, we keep a copy of requests submitted to us to comply with our own legal obligation to maintain data processing records. Please also note that certain information, such as your IP address (if you edit while not logged in) and any public contributions to the Fandom community sites is archived and displayed indefinitely by design; the transparency of each community’s contribution and revision histories is critical to their efficacy and trustworthiness. In addition, the anonymization process cannot ensure complete or comprehensive anonymization of all of the content or information posted on our Services related to your prior username. If your request is granted, the name change will only occur in automatically generated logs (such as page histories) in association with content that you posted. The name change will not delete mentions of your prior username by third parties.

## International Transfers

Where personal information is held by us, it is held in the U.S.A.

We will also transfer the personal information that we collect about you to third party processors located in countries that are outside the EEA, or to members of our group of companies in connection with the above purposes. If we provide any of your personal information to any such non-EEA suppliers, we will take appropriate measures to ensure that the recipient protects your personal information adequately.

## Complaints, Questions And Comments

We have a Data Protection Officer to assist with all queries regarding our processing of personal information.

Wade Warren, DPO  
c/o Fandom, Inc.   
130 Sutter Street, 4th Floor  
San Francisco, CA 94104  
Email: DPO@fandom.com   
Phone: (415) 980-5647

If you have any complaints about our Services, please contact us at:  
Address: 130 Sutter Street, 4th Floor, San Francisco, CA 94104 Email: support@fandom.com Telephone: (415) 762-0780

In the EEA you may also make a complaint to our supervisory body for data protection matters (for example, the Information Commissioner’s Office in the UK) or seek a remedy through local courts if you believe your rights have been breached.

## Annex A

Sites and Services that are subject to the Privacy Policy:

D&D Beyond App  
dndbeyond.com  
futhead.com  
www.gamepedia.com  
muthead.com  
playbook.gg  
strawpoll.me
